你是否曾好奇，在互联网最幽深的角落里，究竟上演着怎样的戏码
Have you ever wondered what really goes on in the darkest corners of the internet?
我说的可不是你在抖音上刷到的，甚至也不是油管上那些奇奇怪怪的频道
I'm not talking about the stuff you see on TikTok or even the weird side of YouTube.
我指的是暗网里那些藏匿的市集和论坛
I mean the hidden marketplaces and forums on the dark web
人们在那儿寻觅杀手，倒腾假护照
where people try to buy hitmen, fake passports,
数据窃取、伪钞，甚至还有传说中的毒品冰山
stolen data, counterfeit cash, and even drug icebergs?
有些东西真是让人不寒而栗
Some really disturbing stuff.
其中有些是骗局，有些却真实得可怕，但几乎所有勾当都见不得光
Some of it is scams, some of it is terrifyingly real, and pretty much all of it is illegal.
尤其是那些毒品冰山
Especially those drug icebergs.
在这期视频里，我将为你揭秘暗网上最猖獗的五大非法服务
In this video, I'm going to break down five of the biggest illegal services you'll find on the dark web.
它们究竟如何运作，为何总有人上当，以及你若真的以身试法会落得何种下场
How they actually work, why people fall for them, and what really happens if you try to use them.
免责声明，本视频仅供教育参考
Disclaimer, this video is for educational purposes only.
本人绝不鼓励、提倡或为任何非法活动背书
I do not encourage, promote, or endorse any illegal activity.
此处讨论的一切都基于公开信息和研究
Everything discussed here is based on publicly available information and research,
旨在揭示暗网的迷思与真相
and it's meant to document the myths and realities of the dark web.
请各位切勿尝试访问或购买视频中提到的任何东西
Please don't actually attempt to access or purchase anything mentioned in this video.
好了，抱歉，我得把甲先叠好
Okay, sorry, I gotta, I had to get that out of the way.
你懂的
You know how it is.
咱们这就开始
Let's get into this.
首先，咱们来聊聊所谓的“顺丰速毙”
First, I want to talk about hitmen services.
当大多数人听到“暗网”这个词
When most people hear the phrase dark web,
脑海里冒出的第一个画面大概就是在线雇凶杀人
one of the first images that pops into their head is the idea of hiring a hitman online.
这桥段在无数的蠕动意面、油管视频甚至电影里都屡见不鲜
It's been in countless creepypastas, YouTube videos, even movies.
仿佛点几下鼠标
The idea that with just a few clicks
花个几百刀比特币
and a couple hundred bucks in Bitcoin,
就能像在得物上买潮鞋一样，轻松下单取人性命
you can order someone's in-game death like you're buying sneakers off StockX.
如果你曾在“暗黑维基”之类的导航站里逛过
And if you've ever gone digging through directories like the Hidden Wiki,
就会知道这类网站其实不难找
you'll know that these sites are not hard to find.
它们的名字五花八门，比如“杀手网络”或“暗网刺客”
They pop up with names like Hitman Network or Darknet Assassin,
个个都自称是由退役雇佣兵
each claiming to be a professional service run by ex-military mercenaries,
前FBI探员甚至是黑手党打手组成的专业团队
former FBI agents, or even mafia enforcers.
它们通常会用一套看起来油光水滑、十分专业的服务菜单来包装自己
They usually present themselves with this slick, professional-looking menu of services.
像什么快速解决、意外事故、投毒，甚至还有非致命的恐吓业务
In-game quick hits, in-game accidents, poisonings, and even non-lethal intimidation jobs.
有些甚至允许你定制任务
Some even let you customize the job.
是想让目标彻底消失，还是只想让他住个院
Do you want the victim to disappear completely, or just be hospitalized in-game?
是想伪装成意外，还是想搞得惊天动地
Do you want it to look like an accident, or do you want it to be loud and messy?
它们竭力模仿真实的电商平台体验
They try to mimic the feel of an actual e-commerce platform.
就好像你在亚马逊上买笔记本电脑
As if you're buying a laptop on Amazon,
只不过保修计划变成了“额外付费，秘密处理”
except instead of a warranty plan, you're paying extra for a discreet disposal.
但真相是什么呢
But here's the truth.
几乎每一个这种网站都是纯纯的冲击波
Nearly every single one of these sites is a scam.
没有一个能兑现承诺
None of them deliver what they promise.
这可不是我瞎猜
And that's not just speculation.
已经有无数针对这类所谓“暗杀市场”的真实调查
There's been actual investigations into dozens of these so-called assassination markets.
每一次的结果都不外乎两种
And every time, they've turned out to be one of two things.
要么是纯粹为了骗元子的诈骗网站，要么是执法部门设下的“蜜罐”陷阱
A straight-up scam designed to steal Bitcoin, or a honeypot sting operation run by law enforcement.
咱们先来分析下为什么诈骗这招这么好用
Let's break down why the scam angle is so effective.
在暗网上，几乎所有交易都用加密货币
On the dark web, almost all payments are made with cryptocurrency.
通常是比特币或门罗币
Usually Bitcoin or Monero.
而加密货币的交易是不可逆的
And crypto transactions are irreversible.
钱一旦离开你的钱包，就肉包子打狗有去无回了
Once the money leaves your wallet, it's gone.
没有退款按钮
There's no refund button.
也没有银行，能让你打电话要求撤销交易
No bank to call and dispute the charge.
更没有客服热线让你哈气
No customer service line to yell at.
所以，你要是把三千刀的比特币打给某个宣传专业杀手服务的匿名网站
So if you send three grand in Bitcoin to some anonymous site advertising professional hit services,
基本上就等同于烧钱玩
you're basically dropping it into a black hole.
为了装得更像那么回事，这些网站通常会吹嘘自己有担保服务
To make it look more convincing, these sites often advertise escrow services.
它们会告诉你，你的钱一直放在安全的中立第三方钱包里，任务完成才结算
They'll tell you that your payment is safe in a neutral third-party wallet until the job is complete.
但猫腻就在这里
But here's the catch.
那些钱包其实是网站自己控制的
Those wallets are controlled by the site itself.
所谓的担保，不过是骗局的另一环
The escrow is just another part of the scam.
你可能会收到一些假的进度更新
You might get messages with fake updates,
甚至是一些所谓的证据照片，而那些照片几乎都是从犯罪现场
maybe even proof photos, which are almost always stolen from crime scenes,
图库或是谷歌图片里盗来的
stock photos, or pulled from Google images.
但活儿永远不会真的去干
But the work never actually happens.
而如果你没被骗，那你的麻烦可能更大
And if you're not getting scammed, then you might be in even worse trouble.
因为还有一种可能，跟你聊天的网站根本不是什么骗子
Because the other possibility is that the site you're talking to isn't run by scammers at all,
而是执法部门的人
but by law enforcement.
这些“蜜罐”就是为了钓那些蠢得挂相
These honeypots are designed to catch people dumb enough
真妄想在现实世界里雇凶杀人的家伙
or desperate enough to actually try hiring an in-game killer.
当你登录、创建账户、开始发送目标的详细信息时
When you log in, create an account, and start sending details about your target,
你基本上等于亲手给调查人员递上了一份签了名的供词
you're basically handing investigators a signed confession.
他们甚至不需要证明犯罪已经发生
They don't even need to prove a crime happened.
光是这个企图，就足以让你因教唆罪或共谋罪而锒铛入狱
Just the attempt is enough to nail you on solicitation or conspiracy charges.
2016年的“贝萨黑手党”案就是个最鲜明的例子
One of the clearest examples of this is the Besa Mafia case in 2016.
“贝萨黑手党”是暗网上最早声名狼藉的雇佣杀手网站之一
Besa Mafia was one of the first notorious hitman-for-hire sites on the dark web.
据称它由一个东欧犯罪网络运营，可在全球范围内执行任务
It claimed to be run by a network of Eastern European criminals who would carry out in-game jobs worldwide.
他们有花哨的营销，一份详细的价目表，甚至还有所谓客户的推荐信
They had flashy marketing, a catalog of prices, and even testimonials from supposed clients.
有段时间，它看起来跟真事儿似的
For a while, it looked like the real deal,
直到研究人员和执法部门深入挖掘
until researchers and law enforcement dug deeper.
结果发现，那不过是一个诈骗团伙
It turned out to be nothing more than a scam operation,
专门从那些潜在的罪犯那里收取比特币
collecting Bitcoin payments from would-be criminals,
提供假的进度更新，然后卷款跑路
providing fake updates, and then disappearing.
在某些案例中
In some cases,
那些试图使用“贝萨黑手党”服务的人，最后真的被追踪并逮捕了
people who tried to use Besa Mafia were actually tracked down and arrested,
因为网站泄露了他们的身份信息，或者干脆就与有关部门合作了
because the site leaked, identifying info, or cooperated with authorities.
这就是传说与现实的关键区别所在
And that's the important myth-versus-reality point here.
传闻说暗网是个能雇佣杀手的地方，跟点外卖似的
The myth says the dark web is a place where you can hire a hitman, like ordering food delivery.
可现实是，如果真有这种勾当
The reality is, if something like that ever actually existed,
它绝不会傻傻地挂在．onion导航页上，等着路人甲乙丙丁来发现
it would not just be sitting there on a .onion directory page for anyone to stumble across.
一个真正的暗杀网络，会通过私密、可信的联系人来运作
A real in-game assassination network would operate through private, trusted contacts,
而不是搞个看起来像谷歌商店似的网站，还带个“加入购物车”按钮
not through a Google-looking storefront with an add-to-cart button.
现在，我们来聊聊这些事在现实中是如何收场的
Now, let's talk about how these things actually play out in practice,
因为执法部门对此早已驾轻就熟
because law enforcement has this process down to a science.
想象一下，某人在“暗黑维基”上找到了一个虚拟杀手网站
Imagine someone finds an in-game hitman site on the hidden wiki.
他注册了账户，联系了管理员，并描述了目标
They create an account, message the operator, and describe the target.
网站回复了一个价格
The site replies with a price.
通常是几千虚拟美金的比特币，如果想伪装成意外，得加钱
Usually a few thousand in-game dollars in Bitcoin, sometimes more if they want it to look like an accident.
买家将款项打入他们以为安全的担保钱包
The buyer sends payment into what they think is a safe escrow wallet.
几天后，他们收到了更新
Days later, they get an update.
虚拟刺杀正在进行中
The in-game hit is in progress.
网站甚至可能发来一张伪造的证据照片
The site might even send a staged proof photo.
可能是一张某人房子的模糊照片
Maybe a blurry shot of someone's house,
一辆停在车道上的车，甚至是一张武器的图库照片
a car parked in their driveway, or even a stock image of a weapon
旁边放着一张写有目标名字的纸条
with the target's name on a piece of paper next to it.
买家感到安心了
这钱花的真值.jpg
The buyer feels reassured.
他们甚至可能为虚拟世界的“开销”支付更多的钱
They might even send more money for in-game expenses.
然后有一天，他们没有收到任务完成的确认，而是收到了别的东西
And then one day, instead of receiving confirmation that the job was done, they receive something else.
执法人员敲开了他们的门，手里拿着搜查令，还有足以构成铁案的数字证据
Law enforcement at their door, a warrant in hand, and enough digital evidence to make a rock-solid case.
就是这么回事
That's the thing.
当你使用这些服务时，你打交道的不仅仅是骗子
When you use these services, you're not just dealing with scammers.
你这番操作，基本上是把能定自己罪的证据，一五一十地全交代了
You're putting yourself in a position where you've provided all the incriminating details.
你的比特币钱包地址，受害者的名字
Your Bitcoin wallet address, the name of the in-game victim,
以及通过Tor会话留下的你自己的数字指纹
and your own digital fingerprints through Tor sessions.
即使Tor隐藏了你的IP，调查人员也有一百种方法把线索串联起来
Even if Tor hides your IP, there are a hundred ways investigators can connect the dots.
草率的VPN使用，重复使用的用户名，或者仅仅是比特币本身
Sloppy VPNs, reused usernames, or just the fact that Bitcoin itself
并不像人们想象的那么匿名这一事实
isn't as anonymous as people think.
每笔交易都记录在一个公共账本上
Every transaction sits on a public ledger,
而执法部门有专门的团队来追踪这些线索
and law enforcement has entire teams dedicated to following that trail.
再拿“贝萨黑手党”的案子来说
Take the case of Basa Mafia again.
调查人员发现，那些试图雇佣杀手的人
Investigators found that people who tried to hire these in-game killers
提供的信息可真是不少，给哥几个送业绩来了说是
were giving up so much information that they basically gift-wrapped their own arrest.
一些客户上传了他们目标的照片、个人地址，甚至日程安排
Some clients uploaded photos of their targets, personal addresses, even schedules.
在一个有记载的案例中，有人试图雇佣“贝萨黑手党”干掉一个情敌
In one documented case, someone tried to hire Basa Mafia to kill a romantic rival in-game,
但最终不仅没有得逞，反而被起诉并面临严重的牢狱之灾，这是好事儿啊
but instead of getting away with it, they ended up indicted and facing serious prison time, which is a good thing.
从心理学角度看，为什么人们会相信这些，这本身就很有趣
Psychologically, what's fascinating is why people fall for this at all.
部分原因在于暗网市场本身
Part of it comes down to the dark web markets itself.
一切看起来都那么申必、加密和隐蔽
Everything looks secret, encrypted, and hidden.
所以用户想当然地认为它是无法追踪的
So users assume it's untraceable.
这些网站的设计也助长了这种专业化的假象
The design of these sites feeds into that illusion of professionalism.
简洁的菜单，担保承诺，客户评论
Clean menus, escrow promises, customer reviews.
它诱使人们相信这平台和亚马逊一样可靠
It tricks people into thinking it's just as trustworthy as Amazon.
只不过是个“暗黑版”亚马逊
Just evil Amazon.
再加上那些觉得只有和真人爆了才是唯一出路之人的绝望心情
Add the desperation of someone who feels like in-game killing is their only way out,
突然间，不可能的事情似乎也成了一种选择
suddenly the impossible feels like an option.
虽然暗网喜欢编造关于专业虚拟刺客网络的神话，但现实要平淡得多
While the dark web likes to spin myths about professional in-game assassin networks, the reality is much more mundane.
如果真正的有组织犯罪集团确实接私活
If real organized crime groups do contract killings,
他们是不会在网上向陌生人打广告的
they're not advertising online to random strangers.
他们通过长期的网络、个人信任和面对面的接触来运作
They operate through long-standing networks, personal trust, and face-to-face contacts.
没有哪个正经的团伙会为虚拟谋杀开一个Shopify商店
No one serious is running a Shopify store for in-game murder.
接下来，我想谈谈数据窃取和所谓的“出全户”
Next, I want to talk about stolen data and fullz marts.
当人们想象暗网时，那些浮夸的传说总是最引人注目
When people imagine the dark web, the flashy myths get all the attention.
杀手、红色房间、器官市场
Hitmen, red rooms, organ markets.
但你要是去问网络犯罪专家
But if you ask cybercrime experts
究竟是什么在驱动着大部分地下经济
what's really driving most of the underground economy,
那答案可就一点也不像电影里那么酷炫了
the answer isn't nearly as cinematic.
是数据窃取
It's stolen data.
如果你听说过任何大型数据泄露事件，比如领英、艾可飞
If you've ever heard about a big breach, LinkedIn, Equifax,
雅虎，甚至是本地商店的POS机被黑，那后果可不会凭空消失
Yahoo, or even your local store's point-of-sale system getting hacked, the fallout doesn't just vanish.
这些被窃取的数据几乎总是会流入暗网上的交易市场
That stolen data almost always ends up funneled into marketplaces on the dark web.
这些网站上卖的东西五花八门，从单个的信用卡号，到他们所谓的“全户”
These sites sell everything from single credit card numbers to what they call fullz,
也就是完整的身份信息包，包括你的姓名、地址、社保号、银行登录信息
or complete identity packages with your name, address, social security number, bank logins,
PayPal账户，有时甚至还有身份证扫描件
PayPal accounts, and sometimes even scanned IDs.
这背后的经济学简直疯狂
The economics of this are wild.
一个被盗的信用卡号可能只卖2到5美元
A single stolen credit card might go for as little as $2 to $5.
一个有余额的PayPal登录信息可能卖10或20美元
A PayPal login with a positive balance could fetch $10 or $20.
而一个完整的身份信息包，也就是“全户”
And a full identity of fullz
价值就高得多了
can be worth much more
因为它给了买家所需的一切，可以用来以你的名义开户、申请贷款
because it gives the buyer everything they need to open accounts, apply for loans,
或进行退税诈骗
or run tax refund scams in your name.
一些市场甚至会宣传所谓的“高级全户”
Some marketplaces even advertise premium fullz
附带额外信息，比如常见密保问题的答案
with extras like answers to common security questions.
那么，这些被盗的数据到底是怎么来的呢
So how does all this stolen data actually get there?
一切都始于一次泄露
It starts with a breach.
黑客侵入一家公司的系统，可能是一家零售商，也可能是一个社媒网站
Hackers break into a company's system, maybe a retailer, maybe a social media site,
或者他们直接从你身上窃取数据
or they skim data directly from you,
比如用ATM侧录器或加油泵上的覆盖装置来盗取你的卡片信息和密码
using ATM skimmers or gas pump overlays that capture your card details and pin.
他们掌握了一批被盗信息后，并不会自己直接出售
Once they've got a dump of stolen information, they don't just sell it themselves.
相反，他们会把数据交给中间商
Instead, they pass it to brokers,
这些中间商专门负责整理、格式化和上架这些数据
middlemen, who specialize in organizing, formatting, and listing that data.
这些商店本身看起来出奇地专业
The shops themselves look surprisingly professional.
你就想，一个有分类的网店，有点像前面提到的那种
Think of an online store with categories, kind of like the last one.
不过这边的分类是信用卡、PayPal账户、社交媒体登录信息
But instead here, it's credit cards, PayPal accounts, social media logins.
他们会列出每张卡的价格，来自哪个国家，有时甚至还有发卡银行
They'll list price per card, what country is from, sometimes even the bank that issued it.
和那些假的杀手服务一样，他们总是接受比特币或门罗币付款
And like with the fake hitman services, they almost always take a payment in Bitcoin or Monero.
一旦你付款，你就会收到一个包含被盗凭证的文件，随时可以使用
Once you buy, you get a file containing the stolen credentials ready to use.
但问题是
But here's the thing.
不是所有的商店都靠谱
Not all shops are created equal.
其中很大一部分都是骗小孩玩的
A huge portion of them are flat out scams.
他们会向你承诺提供4亿个Instagram账户或无限的PayPal登录信息
They'll promise you 400 million Instagram accounts or unlimited PayPal logins.
顺便说一句，如果你真的点了这些链接，哥们，你也是个啥比
By the way, if you're clicking on either of those things, dude, you're stupid.
你的比特币一转过去，可就石沉大海，啥也捞不着了
But the second you send your Bitcoin, you get nothing in return.
因为加密货币交易是不可逆的，你根本没法把钱追回来
Because crypto transactions can't be reversed, there's no way to claw your money back.
所以在这一行，信誉就是一切
That's why reputation is everything in this space.
在一些规模较大、运营时间较长的市场上
On some of the bigger, long-running marketplaces,
卖家会随着时间的推移建立起自己的档案
vendors build profiles over time,
买家会留下反馈，就像闲鱼一样
with buyers leaving feedback, almost like eBay.
这些反馈是区分所谓“靠谱”卖家和纯粹骗子的唯一途径
That feedback is the only way to separate, quote, legit vendors from pure frauds.
但危险的是，即使是那些所谓的“靠谱”卖家，交易的也仍然是赃物
The danger, though, is that even the so-called legit sellers are still dealing in stolen goods.
执法部门深知这一点
Law enforcement knows this.
和那些杀手网站一样
And just like with the hitman sites,
许多这类数据商店也已经被渗透
many of these data shops have been compromised
或者干脆就是作为圈套行动的一部分在运营
or outright run as sting operations.
这也是它们更新换代如此之快的部分原因
That's part of why they churned so fast.
一个市场可能昙花一现，火几个月，然后一夜之间消失
A marketplace might appear, gain traction for a few months, then vanish overnight.
有时候可能是庄家卷款跑路了
Sometimes because the operators exit scammed with everyone's money,
有时候是被FBI或欧洲刑警组织这类机构给一锅端了
and sometimes because it got taken down by agencies like the FBI or Europol.
那么，假设有人从这些市场买了一包被盗信息
So let's say someone buys a pack of stolen information off one of these marketplaces.
他们到底会用它来做什么呢？
What do they actually do with it?
答案取决于他们买了什么
The answer depends on what they bought.
如果只是信用卡号，他们可能会用它来进行“carding”
If it's just credit card numbers, they might use them for carding,
也就是在银行标记这张卡之前进行欺诈性购买的过程
which is the process of making fraudulent purchases before the bank flags the card.
通常是批量进行的
This often happens in bulk.
几十甚至几百张卡被用于小额交易测试，希望能有一些漏网之鱼
Dozens or even hundreds of cards tested across low-dollar transactions, hoping some slip through.
如果是完整的身份信息包，也就是“全户”，那么机会就更大、更可怕了
If it's a full identity package, the fullz, then the opportunities are bigger and scarier.
有了你的社保号、地址和出生日期
With your social security number, address, and date of birth,
犯罪分子就可以用你的名义申请新的信用卡或贷款
criminals can apply for new credit cards or loans in your name.
他们可以提交假的纳税申报单并领取你的退税
They can file fake tax returns and claim your refund.
有些人甚至利用这些身份信息来创建所谓的“合成身份”
Some even use these identities to create what are called synthetic identities,
将真实和虚假信息混合在一起，以欺骗银行发放全新的信贷额度
blending real and fake information together to trick banks into issuing entirely new credit lines.
一旦这些额度被用尽，这个身份就被废弃，然后循环往复
Once those lines are maxed out, the identity is burned, and the cycle repeats.
然后是SIM卡交换攻击
And then there's SIM swapping.
如果一个市场出售了你的手机账户或个人信息的访问权限
If a marketplace sells access to your mobile account or personal details,
攻击者就可以说服你的电话运营商将你的号码转移到他们的设备上
attackers can convince your phone carrier to port your number to their device.
突然之间，他们就能收到你所有的短信，包括双重认证的验证码
Suddenly, they receive all your text messages, including two-factor authentication codes.
有了这个，他们就能侵入你的电子邮件、银行和加密货币钱包
With that, they can break into your email, bank, and crypto wallet.
这就是为什么那么多备受瞩目的黑客攻击
This is why so many high-profile hacks,
尤其是在加密货币领域，都是从一个简单的SIM卡交换开始的
especially in the crypto world, start with a simple SIM swap.
但如果没有洗钱的途径，这一切都行不通
But none of this works without a way to launder the money.
这就是“钱骡”网络发挥作用的地方
That's where money mule networks come in.
犯罪分子通过招募人员层层转移非法资金，以增加追踪难度
Criminals recruit people, sometimes knowingly,
被招募者有时是知情的同伙，有时则是招聘骗局的受害者
sometimes through job scams, to receive fraudulent transfers and forward them along, making the funds harder to trace.
这些“钱骡”通常以为自己只是在为一家在线企业处理付款
These mules often believe they're just processing payments for an online business,
而实际上，他们正在参与洗钱活动
when in reality, they're participating in money laundering.
这是数据窃取市场如何助长更大规模欺诈生态系统的一个重要部分
It's a huge part of how stolen data markets fuel larger fraud ecosystems.
你可能会问，调查人员是如何反击的呢？
Now you might wonder, how do investigators fight back against this?
事实是，那些让这些市场在买家看来值得信赖的因素
The truth is, the same things that make these markets look trustworthy to buyers
往往也使它们在执法部门面前不堪一击
often make them vulnerable to law enforcement.
卖家吹嘘自己的信誉？
Sellers bragging about their reputation?
那是留下了书面证据
That's a paper trail.
托管钱包里存着客户的资金？
Escrow wallets holding customer funds?
那正是调查人员可以查封的一大重点
That's a single point of failure investigators can seize.
而最大的错误，莫过于操作安全上的疏忽
And the biggest mistake of all, OPSEC slip-ups.
市场运营者被抓的案例屡见不鲜
Time and time again, marketplace operators have been caught
原因可能是他们在旧论坛上重复使用了用户名
because they reused usernames from old forums,
有一次忘了用Tor登录，或者把个人和犯罪用的比特币钱包混在了一起
logged in with Altor once, or mixed personal and criminal Bitcoin wallets.
有时，执法部门甚至能通过邮政记录追踪到卖家
In some cases, law enforcement has even traced sellers through postal records,
因为像假身份证或伪钞这样的实物商品需要邮寄
when physical goods, like fake IDs or counterfeit cash, had to be shipped.
一个疏忽就足以致命
One slip is all it takes.
这就是为什么打击行动如此频繁且公开
That's why takedowns are so frequent and so public.
有关部门希望全世界都知道，即使在互联网之暗面
Agencies want the world to know that even in the hidden layers of the internet,
也没有人是不可触碰的
no one is untouchable.
每隔几年，你就会看到关于“最大暗网市场被查封”的头条新闻
You'll see headlines about the largest dark web marketplace seized every few years.
AlphaBay、Hansa、Genesis Market
AlphaBay, Hansa, Genesis Market,
因为这些网站总是在上演迭起兴衰的大戏
because these sites are constantly rising, falling, and being replaced.
这是一场永无止境的猫鼠游戏，但台上的玩家，没几个能永远藏在幕后
It's a never-ending game of cat and mouse, but the players rarely stay anonymous forever.
这就是更宏大的图景
And here's the bigger picture.
被盗的数据才是暗网的真正引擎
Stolen data is the real engine of the dark web.
它没有杀手或红色房间那样浮夸的神秘感
It doesn't have the flashy mystique of pitmen or red rooms,
但它却是维持地下经济运转的命脉
but it's what keeps the underground economy alive.
信用卡数据包、PayPal登录信息、“全户”、SIM卡交换
Credit card dumps, PayPal logins, fullz, SIM swaps.
这些是影响着数百万普通人的家常便饭式犯罪
These are the bread and butter crimes that impact millions of everyday people.
尽管那些神话抓住了人们的想象力
While the myths capture imaginations,
但现实是，暗网的繁荣依赖于一些相当平凡的东西
the reality is that the dark web thrives on something far more mundane.
你的个人信息
Your personal information.
接下来，我要谈谈伪造身份和“造纸厂”
Next, I'm going to talk about forged identity and paper mills.
如果说被盗数据是暗网经济的脊梁，那么伪造文件就是使其运转的肌肉
If stolen data is the backbone of the dark web economy, forged documents are the muscle that keeps it moving.
当我谈及伪造文件时，指的不仅仅是用来进酒吧的假身份证
And when I say forged documents, I don't just mean fake IDs for getting into a bar.
我说的是整个伪造文件产业链，伪造护照
I'm talking about entire paper mills of forged passports,
银行文件、行医执照、文凭，甚至还有新冠疫苗接种卡
bank documents, medical licenses, diplomas, and even COVID-19 vaccine cards.
所有这些都在暗网市场上公开叫卖
All openly advertised on dark web marketplaces.
光是价格就够疯狂的了
The pricing alone is wild.
一张一眼丁真的假驾照可能就要花你几百美元
A simple fake driver's license might run you a few hundred dollars.
而完整的护照，特别是那些声称是美国或欧盟文件的高仿品
Full passports, especially ones claiming to be high-quality replicas of US or EU documents
可能要价数千
can cost thousands.
一些商店甚至提供套餐服务
Some shops even offer package deals.
护照加驾照再加水电费账单，全都在同一个假身份下
Passport plus driver's license plus utility bill all under the same fake identity.
此外还有各种杂项伪造品
Then there are the miscellaneous forgeries.
顶尖大学的文凭
Diplomas from top universities.
医生或飞行员等专业工作的证书
Certificates for specialized jobs like doctors or pilots.
甚至还有假的医疗记录
Even fake medical records.
在疫情期间，伪造的疫苗卡和检测结果市场尤其火爆
These were particularly common during the pandemic when counterfeit vaccine cards and test results were a booming market.
卖家们往往会不遗余力地宣传其可信度
The sellers often go the extra mile to advertise credibility.
商品介绍里会吹嘘有全息图、水印、微缩印刷，以及最重要的MRZ芯片
Listings will brag about holograms, watermarks, micro-printing, and the all-important MRZ chip.
就是现代护照上那个包含加密信息的机读区
That little machine-readable zone on modern passports that contains encrypted information.
卖家都说他们的文件能通过扫描，与真品无异
They'll claim their documents are scan-proof and indistinguishable from the real thing.
在论坛上，你甚至能看到所谓的客户评论
On forums, you'll even see supposed customer reviews,
吹嘘某个证件在夜店或普通检查站是如何蒙混过关的
praising how a document worked at a nightclub or a casual checkpoint.
但问题就在这里
But here's the catch.
能骗过酒吧里25岁的保安，和能骗过国际边检，完全是两码事
There's a massive difference between fooling a 25-year-old bouncer at a bar and fooling an international boarder.
相信我，你可不想成为那个因为太要面子不肯再说一遍
Trust me, you do not want to be like that guy who held up the entire line
自己是美国公民而堵住整条队伍的家伙
because he was too prideful to say that he was a U.S. citizen again.
我是美国公民
你好吗，先生
我很好
你好
是美国公民吗，先生
我还没摇下车窗前就回答了
叽里咕噜说什么呢
我还没摇下车窗前就回答你了
嗯，我没听到你回答，因为车窗是关着的
嗯，车窗是开着一条缝的
我看不出来，这东西看着车窗是关着的
你是美国公民吗，先生
我已经回答你了
我想我不需要回答超过一次
先生，你是美国公民吗
我只想继续我的路
先生，我可以走了吗
先生，你现在正在堵塞交通
我没有
我确实回答了问题
现在能回答我了吗
我不想再重复一遍了，我不说了
回答个问题而已，至于这么费劲吗？
这至于这么麻烦吗？
你是愿意就搁这耗着浪费大家时间还是就简单回答个问题就拉倒了
问你点事怎么就这么费劲呢？
夜店门卫可没受过识别高级伪造品的训练
Club doormen aren't trained in spotting sophisticated counterfeits,
而且大多数人也懒得去扫描你假身份证上的条形码
and most won't bother scanning the barcode on your fake ID.
但机场的护照检查口
But passport control at an airport?
那可就完全是另一回事了
That's a whole other story.
现代护照含有生物识别芯片和多层安全特征，是伪造者无法复制的
Modern passports contain biometric chips and layers of security features that counterfeiters can't replicate.
边检人员都受过识别假证的训练，扫描仪会立刻标记出无效的芯片
Officers are trained to spot fakes, and scanners will immediately flag an invalid chip.
拿着这种假护照走进机场，基本上等于举着牌子求当场被捕
Walking into an airport with one of these forged passports is basically begging to be detained on the spot.
所以实际上，这些伪造品大多用于低风险场合
That's why, in reality, these forgeries are used mostly for low-stakes scenarios.
未成年人饮酒、躲过本地的安检
Underage drinking, slipping past a local security check,
或者为一些小规模的欺诈计划提供辅助文件
or creating supporting documents for smaller fraud schemes.
它们可帮不了你通过希思罗机场或美国运输安全管理局的检查
They're not getting you through Heathrow Airport or past the TSA.
而且通常，即使是那些低风险用途的证件，质量也不怎么样
And often, even the lower stakes items, aren't great quality.
买家们反馈说，姓名有拼写错误、照片模糊，或者条形码扫不出来
Buyers report typos and names, blurry photos, or barcodes that don't scan.
很多所谓的高端护照服务其实都是在吹牛笔
A lot of so-called high-end passport services are bluffing.
他们会收你几千美元的比特币，然后寄给你一个
They'll take thousands in bitcoin and deliver something
连受过相关训练的官员都骗不过去的东西
that wouldn't pass a glance from a trained officer.
然后还有个“自己动手”指南的小产业
And then there's the cottage industry of do-it-yourself guides.
一些卖家不直接卖文件，而是卖教你如何伪造身份证或文凭的PDF和教程
Instead of selling the documents themselves, some vendors sell PDFs and tutorials on how to forge your own IDs or diplomas.
他们会声称你只需要一台覆膜机、一些特种纸和一台打印机
They'll claim you just need a laminator, some specialty paper, and access to a printer.
当然，除了图个新鲜，这招很少能奏效
Of course, this rarely works beyond novelty use,
但它显示了文件伪造的念头在暗网生态系统中是多么普遍
but it shows how pervasive the idea of document forgery is in the dark web ecosystem.
从法律上讲，这风险还是很大的
Legally, the stakes are huge.
在许多国家，仅仅持有伪造文件就是犯罪
In many countries, simply possessing a forged document is a crime.
你甚至不需要使用它
You don't even have to use it.
如果你真的用了，特别是在金融或政府场合
If you do use it, especially in financial or government contexts,
那你将面临欺诈、身份盗窃，在某些情况下甚至是危害国家安全的指控
you're looking at fraud, identity theft, and in some cases national security charges.
即使只是下单购买，风险也不小
Even ordering one is a massive risk
因为和那个杀手网站一样，这些文件贩子中有些正被执法部门监控着
because, like with the Hitman site, some of these document vendors are being monitored by law enforcement.
它们是完美的“蜜罐”，专门用来抓那些试图伪造公民身份
They're perfect honeypots for catching people trying to fake citizenship,
行医资格或专业执照的人
medical qualifications, or professional licenses.
这才是真正的骗局所在
And that's the real scam of it.
这些市场承诺给你新的身份和新的开始
These marketplaces promise new identities and fresh starts,
但你实际得到的只是一张脆弱的塑料片、一个瘪了的钱包
but what you actually get is a flimsy piece of plastic, a lighter wallet,
以及如果你在任何重要场合使用它，都极有可能面临的牢狱之灾
and the very real possibility of jail time if you try to use it anywhere that matters.
接下来，我将谈谈伪钞和暗网现金服务
Next, I'm going to talk about counterfeit currency and dark cash services.
暗网上很少有比买卖成堆的假钞更明目张胆的生意了
Few things on the dark web are as brazen as the idea of buying stacks of fake cash.
你会看到一些看起来近乎卡通的广告
You'll see listings that look almost cartoonish.
花500美元的比特币，就能买到一万刀“完美无瑕”的美钞
$10,000 in flawless U.S. bills for just $500 worth of Bitcoin.
有些甚至还提供样品包
Some even advertise sample packs.
先寄几张给你，让你在下大订单前先测试一下质量
A few notes sent first so you can test the quality before placing a bulk order.
卖家们承诺他们的钞票能通过验钞测试
Sellers promise that their bills pass the pin test,
序列号各不相同，并且与真钞毫无二致
come in mixed serial number batches, and are indistinguishable from the real thing.
乍一看，这简直是终极人生捷径
At first glance, it looks like the ultimate life hack.
钱在打折出售
Money on sale.
但现实是
But here's the reality.
伪钞市场是暗网中最不可靠、风险最高的部分之一
The counterfeit money market is one of the most unreliable and risky parts of the dark web.
首先，我们来谈谈产品本身
First, let's talk about the product itself.
真实的货币，尤其是美元和欧元
Real currencies, especially the U.S. dollar and the euro,
每张钞票上都内置了层层叠叠的防伪特征
have layers upon layers of anti-counterfeit features built into every note.
水印、微缩文字、凸版油墨
Watermarks, micro-printed text, raised ink,
在紫外光下会发光的安全线，以及倾斜钞票时会变色的油墨
security threads that glow under UV light, and color-shifting ink that changes when you tilt the bill.
现代钞票还嵌入了全息图，在一些国家还有几乎无法复制的透明窗口
Modern bills also have embedded holograms and, in some countries, transparent windows that are nearly impossible to replicate.
你从暗网卖家那里拿到的钞票，很少能经得起这些检验
The notes you get from a dark web vendor rarely hold up against those checks.
充其量，它们可能能骗过一个心不在焉的收银员的粗略一瞥
At best, they might pass a quick glance from an inattentive cashier
或者骗过那种基本的碘笔测试
or fool the basic iodine pen test,
那种测试只是检查纸张是不是标准的木浆纸，而不是真钞使用的棉麻混合纸
which just checks if the paper is standard wood pulp instead of the cotton blend used in real notes.
但一旦商店把这些钱存入银行或通过ATM机，假钞就会暴露无遗
But the second a store deposits that money at a bank or runs it through an ATM, the fake is exposed.
ATM机和现金分拣机都是根据真钞进行调试的
ATMs and cash-sorting machines are trained on real bills.
厚度、质地、磁条，大多数伪钞都会立刻被识破
Thickness, texture, magnetic strips, and most counterfeits fail instantly.
所以这些网站上那些大胆的承诺，大多是在吹牛
That's why the bold promises on these sites are mostly bluff.
一些伪造团伙确实试图复制安全特征，但他们通常都做不到位
Some counterfeit operations really do try to replicate security features, but they usually fall short.
模糊的水印、不均匀的印刷或重复的序列号都是致命的破绽
Blurry watermarks, uneven print, or repeating serial numbers are dead giveaways.
而且即使质量比平均水平好
And even if the quality is better than average,
你使用这些钞票的次数越多，被发现的风险就越大
the risk of detection grows the more you try to use the bills.
在街角小店买一次东西可能不会被注意到
A single purchase at a corner store might go unnoticed.
但要是想把一沓假钞存入银行账户，那你在柜员还没完成交易前就会被标记
Try to deposit a stack into a bank account and you'll be flagged before the teller even finishes the transaction.
这门生意的经济学是人们上当的另一个原因
The economics of this trade are another reason people get burned.
卖家用批量定价来吸引买家
Vendors use bulk pricing to lure buyers in.
也许1000美元的样品要300美元
Maybe a sample of $1,000 costs $300,
但如果你买10000美元，价格就降到600美元
but if you buy $10,000, the price drops to $600.
逻辑很简单
The logic is simple.
诱使人们发送更大额的比特币付款
Get people to send larger Bitcoin payments.
但通常情况是，买家把钱转过去后，要么什么也收不到——又一个跑路骗局
But what usually happens is the buyer sends the money and either receives nothing at all, another exit scam,
要么收到一包劣质到可笑的假货
or gets a package of laughably bad fakes.
无论哪种情况，卖家都赢了，而买家承担了所有风险
In both cases, the seller wins, and the buyer takes all the risk.
而风险不仅仅是金钱上的
And the risk isn't just financial.
在大多数国家，持有伪钞本身就是一种严重的犯罪
Possessing counterfeit currency is an illegal crime in most countries.
即使口袋里只有几张假钞，也可能让你吃上官司
Even having a handful of fake bills in your pocket can land you with charges.
要是想在商店里用掉它们，那你除了持有罪，还得加上欺诈罪
Try passing them in a store, and suddenly you're dealing with fraud on top of it.
这就是为什么伪钞钓鱼执法对执法部门如此有效
This is why counterfeit stings are so effective for law enforcement.
执法机构会通过“受控购买”
Agencies will run controlled buys,
来追踪货物，进而利用这些钞票的流通顺藤摸瓜，追查整个分销网络
tracing the shipment, and then using the circulation of those bills to track networks of distributors.
一旦有人试图抛售大批假钞，调查人员就会顺藤摸瓜找到源头
The moment someone tries to offload a large batch, investigators follow the trail back to the source.
现实世界中的伪钞制造者已经无数次以这种方式被捕
Real world counterfeiters have been busted this way countless times.
负责保护美国货币的特勤局
The Secret Service, which is tasked with protecting US currency,
就曾采取过这样的行动，他们让假钞在短时间内流通
has run operations where they let fake bills circulate for a short time,
然后利用序列号来确定这些钞票在何处以及如何传播
then use the serial numbers to identify where and how the notes are spreading.
结合暗网卖家的数据、运输记录
Combined with dark web vendor data, shipping records,
比特币钱包地址、论坛帖子进行抓捕
bitcoin wallet addresses, forum posts,
要摧毁这些所谓的“货币商店”并不需要太多功夫
it doesn't take much to dismantle these so-called money shops.
而这正是暗网上伪钞市场的讽刺之处
And that's the irony of the counterfeit cash market on the dark web.
它听起来像是终极交易
It sounds like the ultimate deal.
廉价的钱，无限的供应，完全匿名
Cheap money, unlimited supply, completely anonymous.
实际上，大多数买家要么被骗，要么被抓，或者两者兼有
In practice, most buyers either get scammed, caught, or both.
这些钞票在ATM机上用不了，骗不过银行
The bills don't work in ATMs, don't fool banks,
甚至常常连收银员的仔细检查都通不过
and often don't even pass a close inspection from a cashier.
你非但没能发财，反而很可能变得更穷、更丢脸，还被立案调查
Instead of striking it rich, you're most likely to end up poorer, embarrassed, and under investigation.
接下来，我将谈谈账户接管和iCloud或设备解锁服务
Next, I'm going to talk about account takeover and iCloud slash device unlock services.
暗网经济的另一大块根本与实物产品无关，而是关乎“访问权限”
Another big slice of the dark web economy isn't about physical products at all, it's about access.
存在着整个市场，唯一出售的商品就是对他人数字生活的控制权
Entire marketplaces exist where the only thing for sale is control over someone else's digital life.
这些网站以菜单式的价格宣传黑客服务
These sites advertise menu-style pricing for hacking services.
举个虚拟世界的例子，100美元入侵一个电子邮件
In-game, for example, $100 to rake into an email,
200美元入侵一个社交媒体账户，或者300美元入侵网上银行
$200 for a social media account, or maybe $300 for online banking.
有两步验证？
Add two-factor authentication?
那得加钱
That's an upcharge.
一些广告甚至声称能提供对某人手机的完全远程控制
Some listings even claim to offer full remote control of a person's phone,
包括短信、通话和即时通讯信息
including SMS messages, calls, and instant messengers.
最引人注目的类别之一是iCloud解锁
One of the most eye-catching categories is iCloud unlocks.
如果你丢过iPhone或被偷过
If you've ever lost your iPhone or had it stolen,
你就会知道苹果的激活锁在没有原主人凭证的情况下，基本上就是一块砖头
you know Apple's activation lock makes it practically useless without the original owner's credentials.
所以暗网上的卖家才会开出天价
That's why dark web vendors quote jaw-dropping prices,
比如说一万美金，号称能解开一个iCloud账户锁
like $10,000, to supposedly unlock a single iCloud account.
他们的宣传口号是，一旦解锁，设备就能像全新的一样直接挂闲鱼
The sales pitch is that once unlocked, the device can be resold as if it were brand new.
在论坛上，你会看到卖家吹嘘他们能在几天内绕过苹果的保护
On forums, you'll see vendors boasting that they can bypass Apple's protections within days,
苹果那边也没问什么问题
no questions asked.
但现实却大相径庭
The reality though is very different.
苹果的激活锁是出了名的难破解，因为它是服务器端的
Apple's activation lock is notoriously hard to break because it's server-side.
锁并不存在于手机本身，而是与苹果的服务器绑定
The lock doesn't live on the phone itself, it's tied to Apple's servers.
这意味着如果有人将设备恢复出厂设置，只要一联网，锁就会马上回来
That means if someone factory resets the device, the lock comes back the second it connects to the internet.
与假护照或信用卡数据包不同，凭证是无法令人信服地伪造的
Unlike a fake passport or a credit card dump, there's no way to convincingly counterfeit the credentials.
你要么有Apple ID的登录信息，要么没有
Either you have the Apple ID login, or you don't.
这使得大多数iCloud解锁的说法纯属天方夜谭
Which makes most of these iCloud unlock claims pure fantasy.
这并不是说账户接管从未发生过
That's not to say these account takeovers never happen.
确实有
They do.
但不是像这些暗网服务宣传的那样
But not the way these dark web services advertise.
真正的攻击路径没那么光鲜
The real attack paths are less glamorous.
比如经典的SIM卡交换
Sim swapping, for example.
虽然我们已经讨论过了
We already talked about that though.
SS7滥用，全球电话网络的一个漏洞，曾被用来重定向短信和通话
SS7 abuse, a flaw in the global phone network, has been exploited to reroute texts and calls.
更常见的是，钓鱼工具包和会话cookie盗窃被用来诱骗人们
More commonly, phishing kits and session cookie thefts are used to trick people into handing over their credentials
在不知不觉中交出自己的凭证
without even realizing it.
这些都是真实的技术
These are all real techniques,
但它们并非像暗网卖家声称的那样，是神奇的、保证解锁的按钮
but they're not magic, guaranteed unlock buttons like the dark web sellers claim.
而这正是需要警惕的最大骗局标志之一
And that's one of the biggest scam markers to look for.
“保证”这个词
The word guaranteed.
真正的黑客从不保证任何事
Real hackers don't guarantee anything.
因为每个目标和每个账户都不同
Because every target in every account is different.
如果你看到一个卖家宣传“保证成功”，不设担保
If you see a vendor advertising guaranteed success, no escrow
还用着看起来像屏幕录像的华而不实的证据视频，那几乎可以肯定是骗局
and flashy proof videos that look like stock screen recordings is almost certainly a scam.
再加上“名额有限”或“24小时后涨价”之类的施压策略
Add in pressure tactics like limited spots left or price goes up in 24 hours
很明显你遇到的只是老掉牙的骗局
and it's clear you're dealing with the same old con game.
只不过披上了技术术语的马甲
Just dressed up in tech jargon.
但有时，即使只是拥有访问权限的假象，也足以造成伤害
But sometimes even the illusion of access is enough to do damage.
一些卖家将账户接管的承诺与敲诈勒索服务相结合
Some vendors combine account takeover promises with blackmail services.
甚至有一些服务，你可以付钱让别人在受害者账户中植入非法文件或违禁品
There are even listings where you could pay someone to plant illegal files or contraband on a victim's account in-game
然后利用这一点敲诈他们
and then use that leverage to in-game blackmail them.
这些服务是否真实，几乎已经不重要了
Whether those services are real or not almost doesn't matter.
光是威胁本身就足以摧毁声誉
The threat itself can destroy reputations.
其他人则提供在社交媒体上散布假证据
Others offer to spam fake evidence or gossip
或八卦的服务，这是另一种形式的数字勒索
across social media, another form of digital extortion.
这就是账户接管越界到赤裸裸的人肉搜索和骚扰的地方
This is where account takeover crosses the line into outright doxxing and harassment.
法律上的后果是严重的
Legally the consequences are severe.
购买他人账户的访问权限是欺诈
Buying access to someone's account is fraud.
利用该访问权限冒充他们
Using that access to impersonate them,
窃取金钱或进行敲诈勒索，则升级为身份盗窃和勒索
steal money, or blackmail them pushes into identity theft and extortion.
和前面提到的其他类别一样，执法部门知道这些网站的存在
And just like with the other categories, law enforcement knows that these sites exist.
近年来一些最引人注目的逮捕行动，就是因为有人试图雇佣暗网黑客
Some of the most high-profile busts in recent years have come from people trying to hire dark web hackers.
结果却径直走进了钓鱼执法的圈套
And instead, walking straight into sting operations.
说到底，暗网上的账户接管行业
At the end of the day, the account takeover industry on the dark web
和所有其他见不得光的服务一样，都靠同一种燃料驱动
runs on the same fuel as every other shady service.
绝望、轻信和不可逆的加密货币支付
Desperation, gullibility, and irreversible crypto payments.
账户泄露确实会发生
Real account breaches happen,
但它们通常来自钓鱼链接、糟糕的密码习惯或内部作案
but they usually come from phishing links, poor password hygiene, or inside jobs.
而不是来自某个有着霓虹灯标志和联系表单的“黑客雇佣”网站
Not from some hacker for hire website with a neon logo in a contact form.
如果你把比特币发给这些所谓的服务，你很可能再也见不到它了
If you send Bitcoin to one of these supposed services, odds are high that you'll never see it.
或者更糟，你会引起调查人员的注意
Or worse, you'll get the attention of investigators
而他们现在已经掌握了你犯罪企图的完整记录
who now have a complete record of your attempt.
所以各位，显然不要尝试或企图做任何违法的事情
So obviously guys, don't try or even attempt to do anything illegal.
现在我想知道，你们中有没有人上过暗网
Now I want to know if any of you guys have ever been on the dark web.
我从朋友和网上的人那里听过很多关于它的故事
I've heard a lot of stories from friends and people online about it.
如果你们有自己的经历，我很想在下面的评论区听听其中的一些
And if you have any of your own experiences, I would love to hear about some of those in the comments down below.
暗网有时候确实是个挺吓人的地方，但有时候呢，又特别的琐碎无聊
The dark web can be a very scary place sometimes, but also sometimes it can be very menial and boring.
我的意思是，你瞅瞅暗网
I mean, look at the dark web.
是不是挺挫的
It looks lame, doesn't it?
再次强调，虽然了解或谈论这些暗网上罕见又可怕的事情
And again, while it's fun to learn or talk about these like really rare, scary things on the dark web
以及恐怖故事很有趣，但我更想听到一些真实的个人经历
and the horror stories of it, I would love to hear some actual personal accounts.
所以各位，如果你们有任何个人经历，或者你们的朋友有
So any of you guys, if you have any personal accounts, if your friends have any,
或者你们知道任何关于暗网、深网之类的故事，请在评论区留言
if you know any stories about the dark or the deep web or whatever, please leave it in the comments.
我很想阅读并了解更多
I would love to read and learn more about it.
我知道我有些朋友就喜欢上去逛，下载个Tor浏览器，然后你懂的
I know my friends used to go on there and like download Tor and, you know,
忘了开VPN，闹出各种啼笑皆非的笑话
forget to use a VPN and little funny stories like that.
我觉得这真的很有趣
I think it's really funny.
我觉得这真的很酷
I think it's really cool.
我知道很多人都这么干过
I know a lot of people have done that.
或者如果你知道任何关于暗网的真实恐怖故事，也请在下面留言
Or if you know any actual horror stories about the dark web too, leave those down below as well.
我很想听到你们的任何分享
I would love to hear anything from you guys.
嗯，就这样
But yeah, thanks.
谢谢大家的观看
Thank you for watching guys.
如果你都看到这里了，不妨关注我的Instagram，加入我的Discord
If you made it this far, you may as well follow my Instagram and join my Discord.
感谢观看
Thank you for watching.
我非常感激
I appreciate it so much.
祝大家晚安
Have a great night, everyone.
做个好梦
And sweet dreams.